Register of the Lucas (Grace Alta Merritt) Papers, 1892-1972
Holt-Atherton Department of Special Collections
Lucas (Grace Alta Merritt) Papers,
1892-1972
Mss157
3.25 linear ft.
University of the Pacific. Library. Holt-Atherton Department of Special Collections Stockton, CA 95211
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Access Points
personal name
Merritt family
personal name
Lucas family
personal name
Rosser family
personal name
Merritt, Mary J. Rosser
personal name
Merritt, Lawrence G.
personal name
Lucas, Grace Alta Merritt (1885-1977)
personal name
Lucas, Julius Robert
subject
Women printers -Correspondence
subject
Helena (Mont.) -History -Sources
subject
Salt Lake City (Utah) -History -Sources
subject
Printers -California -Stockton
Biography
Grace Alta Merritt Lucas (1885-1977) was the granddaughter of Sarah Griffiths and Benjamin Rosser, Welsh immigrants who settled in Iowa. The Rossers had five children one of whom, Mary, was Alta Merritt Lucas' mother. Mary Rosser married Lawrence G. Merritt (1884) and, at twenty-six, Alta Merritt married Julius Robert Lucas in Indianapolis. The Lucases lived in Helena, Montana for most of their married life, later moving to Salt Lake City, where they were divorced in 1921. Mrs. Lucas then settled in Stockton, California where she and her ex-husband were part owners of the Muldowney Lucas printing Company. From 1930 she worked as a printer for a Stockton newspaper until retiring in 1976.
Scope and Content
The Grace Alta Merritt Lucas Collection consists chiefly of personal correspondence and family photographs. The collection also contains legal documents and correspondence with attorneys in Helena, Montana regarding the Lucas's property there.
Container List
- BOX 1--- MRS. J.R. LUCAS, CORRESPONDENCE AND MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS
  - 1.1 Correspondence: Mrs. J.R. Lucas, Nov. 8, 1907-Aug. 29, 1913
  - 1.2 Correspondence: Mrs. J.R. Lucas, Sept. 7, 1913-July 7, 1922
  - 1.3 Business Correspondence
  - 1.4 Financial Documents: Alta Merritt
  - 1.5 Financial Documents: Alta Lucas
  - 1.6 Legal Documents: Alta Lucas
  - 1.7 Financial Documents: Mr. L.G. Merritt
  - 1.8 Financial Documents: Mrs. Mary Merritt
  - 1.9 Legal Documents: Mrs. Mary Merritt
  - 1.10 Financial Documents: Mr. Robert Lucas
  - 1.11 Legal Documents: Mr. L. G. Merritt
  - 1.12 Printed Materials
  - 1.13 Printed Materials #2
  - 1.14 Miscellaneous
- BOX 2---FAMILY CORRESPONDENCE, 1882-1926; MARY ROSSER WRITINGS
  - 2.1 Correspondence: Miss Alta Merritt, Sept. 27, 1901- Dec. 11, 1907
  - 2.2 Correspondence: Miss Alta Merritt, March 9, 1908- May 11, 1911
  - 2.3 Correspondence: Mrs. Alta MerrittLucas, March 1911-Sept. 15, 1913
  - 2.4 Correspondence: Mrs. Alta Merritt Lucas, Feb. 26, 1920-Sept 25, 1926
  - 2.5 Correspondence: Mrs. Alta Merritt Lucas, March 2, 1944-Feb. 9, 1972
  - 2.6 Correspondence: Mrs. J. R. Lucas, July 1913-Aug. 29, 1913
  - 2.7 Correspondence: Mr. Robert Lucas, Dec. 11, 1907- Oct. 3, 1913
  - 2.8 Correspondence: Mr. L.G. Merritt, Oct 12, 1901
  - 2.9 Correspondence: Miss Mary Rosser, March 1882-July 12, 1885
  - 2.10 Correspondence: Mrs. Mary Merritt, March 2, 1902-Oct. 14, 1918
  - 2.11 Correspondence: Mr. Eldah Merritt, Aug. 21, 1915
  - 2.12 Writings: Mary Rosser's Poems
  - 2.13 Writings: Mary Rosser's Diary
- BOX 3---PHOTOGRAPHS; AUTOGRAPH BOOKS, NOTES
  - 3.1 Photographs: Snapshots, pictures [unidentified]
  - 3.2 Photographs: Studio Portraits [unidentified]
  - 3.3 Photographs: Picture Postcards [unidentified]
  - 3.4 Autograph Book of Alta Merritt and Mary Rosser
  - 3.5 Alta Lucas' research notes on printing
- BOX 4---PHOTOGRAPHS AND EPHEMERA
  - 4.1 Legal Document: Mr. and Mrs. L.G. Merritt's Marriage Certificate
  - 4.2 Photographic Material: Framed picture of a band of unidentified men
  - 4.3 Photographic Material: Photo album of unidentified snapshots
  - 4.4 3 Dimensional Object: Award of red ribbon from The Supreme Lodge (A.O.U.W.) [given: June 14, 1892 in Helena, Montana]